（利比亚 卡扎菲旧军用化工厂）
奥马尔 将军那里情况如何
Omar, what's the status on the general.
他还和家人在一起
He's still with family.
来尝尝这个美味的吧 儿子
Tule ja proovi midagi maitsvat, poeg me.
不吃吗
No.
哈姆萨
Hamza.
哈姆萨 别睡了
Hamza ra maga enam.
空袭
hurünnak.
快带他们一起去地下避难所
Go with them. Take them to the bunker.
走 快走
Move, move.
费赞将军在哪里
Where is General Fezzan.
告诉我
Tell me.
《敢死队4：最终章》
（美国 新奥尔良）
我也许很复杂 但我不是他妈的绝望
I might be complicated, but I ain't fucking hopeless.
这就是我们所说的复杂吗
Is that what we call it Complicated.
不管叫什么都没用 对吧
Well, whatever it's called, it's not working, is it.
拜托吉娜 你不考虑大局
Come on, Gina, you're not looking at the big picture.
大局是什么
What's the big picture.
是你吗 你是我的大局吗
Is it you Are you my big picture.
我的天啊 宝贝
Oh, my God, thank you.
你他妈的别自以为是了
You should get the fuck over yourself.
因为你知道你实际上是什么吗
'Cause you know what you actually are.
你是个原始人
A caveman.
你确实像原始人
You do resemble a caveman. You know what it is.
- 你不像吗 - 你不想和他争一争吗
- And you don't - You don't want competition.
吉娜 拜托 冷静点 这就是你的问题所在
Gina, please, calm down. That's what your problem is.
让我冷静下来 你刚才是不是告诉我…
Me calm down Did you just tell me…
别他妈的叫我冷静下来 我很冷静
Don't tell me to fucking calm down I'm calm.
我这辈子从来没有他妈的这么冷静过
I've never been more fucking calm in my life.
哦 看着我
"Oh, look at me.
我是英国人 我是逃避型 我不喜欢争论
I'm English. I'm avoidant. I don't like to argue."
你猜怎么着
Well, guess what.
我只想要平静的生活 好吗
I just want a little peace in my life. Right.
- 那会很好的 - 我是美国人 婊子 我们会为此而争吵
- It'd be nice. - I'm from America, bitch. We're gonna fight about it.
- 走 快走 - 走 那我算什么
- Go. Just go. - Go. So what does that make me.
这让我有压力吗
Does that make me stressful.
不不不
No, no, no.
可能有点暴力
A little violent perhaps.
我是专业人士
I'm a professional.
没错 就是有点暴力
Yeah. And a little violent.
有一点
A little bit.
一点点
Teeny bit.
你知道怎么回事吗
You know what it is.
我有和你一样的技能 甚至会更多
I've got your skills and then some.
但你们俩都不喜欢我这样 因为你们都是原始人
And neither of you like it because you're both cavemen.
她在跟你说话
She's talking to you.
事实上她正朝你那边看
Actually, she's looking in your direction.
我在跟你说话
I'm talking to you.
但是你呢
But about you.
你或许是我的领导
You might be my boss,
但我知道你来自一个叫「绝望」的星球
but I can tell that you're also from this planet called "hopeless"
在那里 亲密的关系和感情
where intimate relationships and feelings.
都他妈的不存在
don't fucking exist.
该死的宝贝 我在你身上浪费了太多时间
Fucking baby. I've wasted so much of my life on you.
你是个失败者 但我喜欢你
You are a loser. But I like you.
谢谢
Thanks.
你为什么在这里
Why are you here.
我把戒指丢在酒吧了 我需要你帮忙…
I lost my ring at this bar, and I need you to…
不好意思 就这样吗 我们谈完了吗
I'm sorry. Is that it Are we done talking.
这次谈话结束了吗
Are you done with this conversation.
谈话
Conversation.
更像是愤怒的喋喋不休
It's more like angry chatter.
操你
Fuck you.
她又在跟你说话了
She's talking to you again.
- 太压抑了 - 不 没关系的
- It's depressing. - No. It's okay.
我喜欢她 巴尼
I liked her, Barney.
她是敢死队的 圣诞
She's an Expendable, Christmas.
听着 我尊重你的超凡能力 真的
Look, I got great respect for your uncanny abilities. I really do.
但你真的是个自私的混蛋
But you are a selfish prick.
- 真的吗 - 我们都是
- Really - We all are.
我们必须选择这种生活
We have to be to choose this life.
而不是选择朋友 家人
over friends, over family.
我们这么做是为了钱
We do this for money.
这就是「混蛋主义」的定义
That's the definition of prickism.
你觉得我的观点怎么样
What do you think of my analysis.
很不错吧
Pretty good.
我觉得…你是个白痴
I think you're a moron.
你说的不是真的
You don't believe that.
我身体里的每一个细胞都觉得是真的
With every cell in my body.
我们为什么在这里
Why are we here.
我昨晚打赌把戒指丢了 现在我来试着把它买回来
I lost my ring last night in a bet, and I'm here to try to buy it back.
真的吗
Seriously.
是的 真的
Yeah, seriously.
你这个傻瓜
A silly little trinket.
我很迷信 而且我喜欢它
I'm superstitious about it, and I like it.
感觉像是我少了一根手指
Feel like I'm missing a finger.
我想把他拿回来 但这个白痴不愿意谈判
I tried getting it back, but this half-ass won't negotiate.
- 谁 - 珍宝虾
- Who - Jumbo Shrimp.
- 他是谁 - 你会看到的
- Who's he - You'll see.
- 怎么样了 巴尼 - 嘿 比利
- What's up, Barney - Hey, Billy.
你是怎么失去你最珍贵的戒指的呢
So how'd you lose your most prized possession.
拇指摔跤
Thumb wrestling.
- 你是说掰手腕 - 不是
- You mean arm wrestling - No.
我的意思是说 拇指摔跤
I mean thumb wrestling.
就像那样 把你的手给我
Like that. Give me your hand.
不 拇指摔跤
No. Thumb wrestling.
你以前很强的 发生什么了
You used to be strong. What happened.
你以前很多头发的 发生什么了
And you used to be hairy. What happened.
世事无常嘛
Things change.
- 怎么样了 巴尼 - 有什么新鲜事吗
- What's up, Barney - Hey, how you doing.
珍宝虾在这里吗
Jumbo Shrimp around.
有什么事吗
Is there a problem.
我朋友想要回他的戒指
My friend wants his ring back.
打赌就是打赌 老兄
Bet's a bet, man.
你懂的 无意冒犯 但我想念我的戒指
You know, no offense, but I'm missing my ring.
它会留在那里
It stays where it is.
这太无法接受了
That's unacceptable.
太像了…
Striking resemblance.
这太残忍了
That's brutal.
- 是这些人吗 巴尼 - 是的
- These the guys, Barney - Yeah.
现在我明白为什么他们叫他巨无霸（珍宝虾）了
Now I see why they call him Jumbo.
不 是另一个人 那个人
No, the other guy, second guy.
你输给了圣诞老人的助手了
You lost to Santa's helper.
这太尴尬了
That's embarrassing.
我喝醉了
I was drunk.
但你现在没醉
Well, you're not drunk now.
我到底为什么会在这里
Why the fuck am I here.
我的背受伤了
I hurt my back.
什么时候的事
Since when.
几周前我连叉子都拿不起来
A few weeks ago. I can't even lift a fork.
我会帮你的 但如果你不想 我能理解
I would do it for you. But if you don't want to do it, I understand.
如果你被吓到了…
If you're intimidated…
吓到了
Intimidated.
等等 李
Hey, Lee.
戴上它会让你自己更轻松
Make it easy on yourself.
经典神器
The classics.
我来搞定 大块头
I got this, Thumbo.
请来瓶啤酒
Beer, please.
在这美好的一天你过得怎么样
How you doing this nice day.
你希望我叫你珍宝还是小虾
What do you prefer to be called, "Jumbo" or "Shrimp"
再这么叫我一次
Call me that again.
就把你破脑袋砍下来
Cut your fucking head off.
这有点刺耳 小不点
That's a little harsh, bite-size.
巴尼想要回他的戒指
Barney wants his ring back.
你叫我什么
What did you call me.
要多少钱 尤达 （星战中的角色）
How much for it back, Yoda.
等等
Hey.
戒指要留在这里 白痴
It stays here, asshole.
我的背
My back.
如你所见
You see,
我们在这里所面临的是羞辱和仁慈的问题
what we have here is a matter of humiliation and human kindness.
我这位朋友很喜欢他的戒指 因为他那些愚蠢的理由
My friend here loves his ring for all of his stupid reasons.
如果各位先生们能理解
And it would be very nice and civilized.
那样会很好 很文明
if you gents would understand that principle.
但既然你选择了…
But since you choose to be…
- 巴尼 怎么说来着 - 冥顽不灵
- Barney, what's the word - Obstinate.
换个短点的词
Too long.
傻逼
Dumbbells.
你让我别无选择 你个白痴
You leave me no other choice, dinky.
- 不用谢 - 你变慢了
- You're welcome. - You're slowing down.
该我了 混蛋
My turn, bitch.
来吧 来吧 牛仔 放马过来
Come on, chuck. Come on, cowboy. Bring it.
当他醒来时 给他准备好啤酒
Get him a beer when he wakes up.
你差点杀了我
You almost killed me.
我还以为你背疼
I thought you had a bad back.
真是个奇迹 刚刚康复了
You know, it's a miracle. It just went away.
你知道吗 我真的不需要这样的「爱情盛宴」
You know, I really didn't need this lovefest.
我喜欢和你在一起
I like spending time with you.
下次带我去骑马 好吗
Next time, take me on a pony ride, okay.
好的
Okay.
侦察小队 情况如何
Overwatch, what is the status.
长官 有三个士兵保护着将军
Sir, there are three soldiers guarding the general.
你需要支援
You're gonna need backup.
我重复一遍 等待支援
I repeat, wait for backup.
他妈的 他在做什么
What the fuck is he doing.
不 不 求你了不要
No, no, no. No, no, please. Please, don't.
近来可好 将军
What's up, General.
- 是我眼花了吗 - 什么
- Are my eyes deceiving me - Why.
贡纳头上戴了个什么
What's that thing on Gunner's head.
看起来像一只生病的猫
It looks like a sick cat.
好可爱的猫
Cats are cute.
那看起来像风滚草
That looks like tumbleweed.
晚上好 大个子
Hey, good evening, big man.
我们来谈谈你头上的东西是什么
Let's talk. What's that thing on your head.
这个假发
Oh, the wig.
- 是的 假发 - 问题是 为什么戴假发
- Yeah, the wig. - Question is, why.
我在网上和一个女孩聊天
Well, I was chatting with this girl on the Internet.
她喜欢70年代的造型
and she likes that '70s look, you know.
费拉·福赛特的形象
The Farrah Fawcett thing.
理解 你见过她吗
Got it. You met her yet.
我为什么要见她 我喜欢神秘
Why… Why would I do that I like the mystery.
- 明白吗 - 明白 很有道理
- Understand - Yeah, that makes sense.
- 看起来很特别 - 确实
- Sounds special. - It does.
我更喜欢他喝醉的样子
I liked him better when he was a drunk.
我明白你的意思 我也是
I know what you mean. Me too.
我为你感到高兴
I'm happy for you.
这是新来的吗
Hey, is this the new guy.
嘿 轻松哥来了
Hey, it's Easy Day.
好男人 前特种部队成员
Good man. Ex-special forces.
- 嘿 巴尼 - 嘿 轻松哥
- Hey, Barney. - Hey, Easy.
这是我们的狙击手吗
This our sniper.
别担心 我有专门为我眼镜设计的瞄准镜
Don't worry about it. I got a prescription scope.
怎么了
What.
好吧鹰眼 记住这张脸
Well, Hawkeyes, remember this face.
别打到我了
Don't shoot it by accident.
不用担心我
You don't have to worry about me.
这个人是谁
Who's this guy.
你越来越不行了 伙计
You're slipping, pal.
你雇了他 他是加列戈的儿子
You hired him. That's Galgo's son.
我遗传了我父亲的视力和心灵还有性欲
I have the eyesight, the heart and the sex drive of my father.
别告诉我他跟他父亲一样话多
Tell me he doesn't talk as much as his father.
- 他话更多 - 不会吧
- He's worse. - No.
而且是双倍的多
Twice as bad.
这将是一个漫长的旅程
It's gonna be a long trip.
我是加兰
I am Galan.
这有什么意义吗
That suppose to mean something.
应该有点意义
It's supposed to mean a little something.
好了别废话了 都看着我
All right, cut the bullshit. All eyes on me.
穿西装的是谁
Who's the suit.
他叫马什
His name is Marsh.
在认识你之前我和他合作过
I did a few things with him before I met you.
- 他是中情局的 - 嘿 巴尼 最近怎么样
- He's CIA. - Hey, Barney, how you doing.
你好吗 马什
How you doing, Marsh.
他们怎么样了
How they hanging.
状态恢复中
Gravity's setting in.
欢迎加入我们
Welcome to the club.
虽然我很想和你们寒暄一下
As much as I would like to exchange pleasantries with you guys,
但手头有一件急事
there's a pressing matter at hand.
认识下苏瓦尔图·拉赫马特
Meet Suharato Rahmat.
一个前英国公民变成了军火商
Former British national turned arms dealer.
他有一支私人军队
He has his own private army and he's been hired.
他被一个非常危险的客户雇去
to steal some detonators for nuclear missiles.
偷一些核导弹的引爆装置
for a very dangerous client.
有传言说那个客户的名字叫「豹猫」
Word on the street is the client's name is Ocelot.
如果那些核炸药落入豹猫之手
Now, those detonators get in the hands of Ocelot,
他打算使用它们制造国际混乱
he's planning on using them to create an international incident.
我们绝不能允许这种情况发生
We can't let that happen.
这就是你们来的原因
So that's where you guys come in.
降落后你会发现卡扎菲在利比亚的旧军用化工厂
Your landing zone is Qaddafi's old chemical war plant in Libya,
我听说每年这个时候那里很美
which I hear is very nice this time of year.
你们的任务是确保核炸药留在那里
Your mission is to make sure the detonators stay there.
好吗
All right.
我就知道这么多 祝好运
That's all I got. Good luck.
巴尼 保证他们的安全
Barney, keep 'em tucked.
我会尽力的
I'll do my best.
- 豹猫行动 - 嗯哼
- Operation Ocelot. - Mm-hmm.
你打算什么时候告诉我
When were you gonna tell me.
当你不再惹你女朋友的时候
When you stopped playing footsies with your girlfriend.
为什么圣诞对豹猫的任务这么生气
Hey, why's Christmas so pissed about this Ocelot mission.
圣诞是这样的
He's just being Christmas.
- 明白 - 他很了解巴尼
- Copy that. - He knows Barney very well.
他很清楚该怎么做才能消灭豹猫
He knows exactly how far he's willing to go to end Ocelot.
谁自称豹猫
Who the hell names himself Ocelot.
几年前中情局就雇佣了巴尼
Years ago, the CIA hired Barney.
来找出谁的代号是豹猫
to find out who code name "Ocelot" actually is.
他查的很接近了 然后有人伏击了他
He was close when somebody walked him into an ambush.
差点灭了他的整个团队
and nearly killed his entire team.
该死
Damn.
有人说豹猫只是巴尼
Yeah, some would say Ocelot's a ghost.
为了掩盖自己的错误而创造出来的幽灵
that Barney created to cover his own ass for a mistake.
他妈的 不可能
No fucking way.
豹猫确实存在 巴尼总有一天会把它埋了
Ocelot exists and Barney will bury him someday.
你的耳朵怎么了 伙计
What the fuck happened to your ear, man.
很高兴你问这个问题
I'm glad you asked me that.
我大学时是摔跤运动员 这类运动的常见并发症是耳朵损伤
I wrestled in college. Common affliction in that sport is contusions to the ear.
一些血液在耳软骨中聚集…
Small pocket of blood that separates the skin from the cartilage.
翱翔吧 大鸟
Come on, big bird.
快上去吧 你这个「死亡陷阱」
Get up there, you deathtrap.
别侮辱它
Don't insult it.
我们成功起飞了
We have a successful liftoff.
这可能是我第一次三人行
Maybe it was my first ménage à trois.
托尔·罗德 你知道我在说什么对吧
You know. You know, Toll Road, what I'm talking about, right.
你知道什么是「黄金雨」吗
You know what is a golden shower.
就是一个女人她…
It's when the woman, she…
她跪在你身上然后往你身上撒尿
She squats down on top of you and releases her bladder.
这是一种非常解放的感觉
It's very liberating.
哇 国际变态
Wow, a world-class pervert.
你知道什么是「黄金雨」吗
You know what is a golden shower.
你看起来像是以前干过这种事的人
You look like the type who has had one before.
我要裁掉这些废物
I'm cutting these losers.
- 我听过太多了 - 现在是调音时间 该听音乐了
- I heard too much of that. - It's tune time. Time for music.
太老了
It's ancient.
很舒缓
It's soothing.
- 舒缓吗 - 是的
- Soothing - Yeah.
可能吧
Yeah, maybe.
你知道吗 我昨晚焦虑发作
You know I had a panic attack last night.
- 真的吗 你确定 - 是的
- Did you really Are you sure - Yeah.
就像你的皮肤开始起鸡皮疙瘩
Like your skin starts to crawl.
- 心跳加速 - 没错
- Your heart is beating - You know it.
吃点安眠药 假装你对生活很满意
Just take some Xanax and pretend you're happy with your life.
我很高兴
I am happy.
顺便说一句你是史上最差的医生
By the way, you're the worst doctor, ever.
也许吉娜对你太苛刻了
Maybe it's Gina who's making you anxious.
她能让我平静下来
She actually relaxes me.
这就是…工作
It's this… this… The job.
不
No.
有些男人根本就不适合谈恋爱
Some guys are just not meant for companionship.
- 面对现实吧 - 太糟了
- Face the facts. - Wrong.
也许你想以痛苦的老样子死去 但我不想
Maybe you want to die a bitter old sod, but not me.
我想要开朗 快乐
I want to be cheerful, happy.
但是我会去疗养院看你的
But I will come visit you in the home.
- 你保证吗 - 以名誉担保
- Promise - Scout's honor.
让我们看看发生了什么
Let's see what's going on.
一个女孩在我身上滴了热蜡
One of them was covering me in hot candle wax.
算了吧
Forget it.
核炸药在哪
Where are the detonators.
绝不告诉你
Never.
你妻子
Your wife.
别动我老婆 不 真主是最伟大的
Not my wife. No, Allahu Akbar.
下一个就是你儿子
Your son is next.
求求你 别动我儿子 求你了
P-Please, not my son. Please.
把核炸药给我 我很快就能搞定
Give me the detonators, and I'll make it quick.
我的儿子 亚当…
My son, Adam…
这是你无法改变的事实
This is a fact you cannot change.
把核炸药给我 否则…
Give me the detonators or…
别动我儿子
Not my son.
决定权在你
Your choice.
好 好的
Okay. Okay.
在控制室里
They are in control room.
安全密码是…
The code to the safe is…
八
eight,
一
one,
四
four,
二
two…
七
seven.
明智的选择
Wise choice.
来叫醒孩子们吧
Let's wake up the kids.
- 准备好了吗 - 是的
- Ready - Yep.
这是从哪里来的呢
Where'd that come from.
这会很有趣的
Ah, this is gonna be fun.
- 遭到攻击 - 开始反击
- LZ's hot. - Here we go.
- 来了 - 高射炮
- Incoming - Flak.
情报有误
Intel was off.
要有创意
Get creative.
明白了
Got it.
探探底就走
Touch and go.
好了 集合 振作起来
Okay, rally up. Rally up.
- 我来开路好吗 - 不用了
- Am I driving lead - Nah.
带贡纳去监视 然后投入战斗
Take Gunner to overwatch and fall in.
着陆
Touch.
祝你狩猎愉快
Happy hunting.
去看看 武器工厂出事了
Check it out. There's something happening at the weapons plant.
我们正在查看
We're on it.
有四辆车和许多士兵
I count four vehicles and a lot of ops.
好的 我们来努力削减对方人数
Well, let's make less of them.
先生 我有一种新的交通工具
Sir, I have a new transport.
太棒了
Excellent.
告诉豹猫我们拿到核炸药了
Tell Ocelot we have them.
我们走吧
Let's go.
已就位
In position.
上车
Load up.
拉赫马特有核炸药
Rahmat's got the detonators.
贡纳 你看到他们了吗
Gunner, you got eyes on them.
目标就像车前灯的灯罩
Like crystal in headlights.
贡纳 你没击中目标
Gunner, you're way off target.
你需要导盲犬吗
What do you need, a seeing-eye dog.
该死的污渍
Damn spots.
嘿 史蒂夫·旺德 你应该检查一下你的瞄准镜
Hey, Stevie Wonder, you might want to get that prescription checked.
小心点 李 你在哪儿
Heads up. Lee, where are you.
看来我们要开始行动了
Looks like we're making our entrance.
抓稳你的枪把
Hold on to your huevos.
让我们起飞吧 宝贝
Let's fly, baby.
这人到底是谁
Who the fuck is this now.
我们该怎么办 老大
What do we do, boss.
杀了他们
Kill them.
开火
Open fire.
贡纳 我们需要帮助
Gunner, we could use some help.
我已经戒酒六个月了
Six months sober.
这就是我要说的 贡纳
Now that's what I'm talking about, Gunner.
你能甩掉他们吗
Can you lose them.
- 我们进去了 - 收到
- We're inside - Copy.
分头行动
Split up.
加兰 我们去找目标
Galan, we'll take point.
- 你去追逃跑的混蛋 - 收到
- You go after that squirter. - Copy.
我们失去了50口径的机枪
We lost the 50 cal.
把车停在他旁边
Pull up alongside him.
是时候即兴发挥了
Time to improvise.
我可以即兴发挥
I can improvise.
腹部中枪 你会活下来的
Gut shot. You'll live.
也许不会
Maybe not.
加兰 你他妈的在干什么
Galan, what the fuck are you doing.
我在随机应变
I'm improvising.
里面发生了什么事 我要马上知道情况
What's going on in there I need a status report now.
再干掉一个就到拉赫马特了
One more and we're on Rahmat.
怎么回事 轻松哥
What the fuck, Easy.
唯一轻松的一天就是昨天
Only easy day was yesterday.
是的
Yep.
首战告捷还是出师不利
Initial success or total failure.
首战告捷
Initial success.
我没子弹了 我要进攻了
I'm out of ammo. I'm coming in.
你是说出师不利吗
You mean total failure.
圣诞你在哪 他们拿到核炸药了
Christmas, where are you The detonators are compromised.
他们在西边 正往北走
They're on the west side heading north.
别让拉赫马特带着核炸药离开
Don't let Rahmat leave with those detonators.
否则会有很多人丧命
or there's gonna be a lot of dead people.
上车吧 废柴们 我们要去购物了
Get in, losers We're going shopping.
小心身后
You might want to watch your six.
往洞里开火 伙计们
Fire in the hole, fellas.
转移
Moving.
掩护我
Cover me.
我来了
Incoming.
别担心伙计 我永远不会抛弃你
Don't worry, my friend. I would never leave you behind.
我找不到好的射击角度
I can't get the angle.
- 我没热诱导弹了 - 该死 巴尼
- I'm out of flares. - Damn it, Barney.
继续执行任务 圣诞
Stay on mission, Christmas.
你在上面要完蛋了
You're toast up there.
听他的伙计 把核炸药拿来
Listen to him, man. Get the detonators.
去拿核炸药 李
Get the detonators, Lee.
这是命令
That's an order.
他妈的不行 我要救这个笨蛋
Fuck no. I'm saving your dumb ass.
不用谢
You're welcome.
干得好伙计 但谁去阻止拉赫马特呢
Nice work, man, but who's on Rahmat.
我的天啊
Holy shit.
（悼念巴尼·罗斯队长）
我们想你 巴尼
We miss you, Barney.
大家都听好了
Everybody listen up.
有句老话说得好
There's an old expression.
在一个通常英年会早逝的行业里 要当心老人
Beware an old man in a profession where good men die young.
我敢肯定 他们为巴尼·罗斯在上面
I'm sure Barney Ross has had a seat reserved.
留了很久的席位
at the big table up there for some time now.
他配得上那个位子
And he earned that seat.
而且他永远都不会放弃
He never stopped earning it.
他激发了我们每个人最好的一面 因为他是我们中最好的
He brought the best out in each and every one of us because he was the best of us.
敬巴尼
To Barney.
你好吗
How are you.
好极了
Great.
没必要掩饰 李
You don't gotta pretend, Lee.
巴尼也不会想看你闷闷不乐的样子
You know Barney wouldn't want to watch you sulking like this.
这倒是真的
It's true.
我能帮忙吗
Can I help.
好吧 既然你问了…
Well, since you're asking…
我想要…
I'd like…
我们什么时候去抓幕后黑手呢
So when are we going after the guys that did this.
你哪儿也不用去 你被开除了
You ain't going nowhere. You're done.
- 这是什么意思 - 与你无关了
- What's that mean - You're off it.
- 你出局了 - 胡扯 马什
- You're done. You're out. - Bullshit, Marsh.
谁来管理巴尼的团队
Who's gonna run Barney's team.
吉娜
Gina.
这是在开玩笑吗
What is this, a bad joke.
你违抗了上级的直接命令
Well, you disobeyed a direct order from your superior.
让我们没完成任务 所以你被开除了
and that cost us the mission, so you're out.
- 我是想救他 - 不过你没有做到
- I was trying to save him. - Well, you didn't.
这是我们的使命 也是我们的决定 你被开除了
It's our play, it's our call. You're out.
这是巴尼自己要做出的牺牲 兄弟
It was Barney's sacrifice to make, brother.
对于这次任务来说 舍身成仁 这意义很重要
Good death for the mission, it would count.
而你剥夺了他的意义
And you just took it from him.
你让他的牺牲毫无价值
Made his sacrifice worthless.
圣诞
Christmas.
是的
Yeah.
谢谢你的支持
Thanks for the support.
你可真会挑日子 伙计
You certainly picked your moment, pal.
巴尼讨厌翻唱乐队
Barney hated cover bands.
我会保持联系的
I'll be in touch.
巴尼所做的一切不是都毫无价值
Nothing Barney did was worthless.
- 你明白吗 什么都没有 - 嘿 冷静点 哥们
- You understand Nothing - Hey. Easy, cowboy.
去你妈的 别在我面前谈论巴尼
Fuck you, talking about Barney in my face.
这不是合适的时间地点
This ain't the place or time.
拜托 冷静点伙计
Por favor. Please, please. Tranquilo.
（巴尼·罗斯）
（分类招聘广告）
备餐厨师
Pantry cook.
酒店总监
Hospitality director.
要求“热情好客”
Can be "hospitable-ish."
一个社交网红的私人保镖
Private security detail for a social media influencer.
（招聘：社交网红的私人保镖）
我要去喝一杯
I'm gonna go get a drink.
我们直播马上就要开始了
We're about to go live.
即将给大家看看这群垃圾
We're about to stream this shit,
你看起来很痛苦
and you girls look like shit.
不 不
Uh, no. No.
再见
Buh-bye.
- 嘿 肌肉男 - 到这来
- Hey, muscles. - Get over here.
给你 伙计 拿着我的告示牌
Here, dude. Hold my sign.
我是你的私人保镖
I'm your private security detail.
我是来保护你的
I'm here to protect you.
不是来帮你拿牌子的
Not hold your sign.
你觉得有人想要伤害我吗
You see anybody looking to do me harm.
有可能
Potentially.
管他呢 拿着牌子就行了
Whatever. Just hold the sign.
「有可能」 那就看仔细 傻帽
"Potentially." Double-O douchebag.
还好吗 王八蛋们
What's up, motherfuckers.
我在我的新奥尔良豪宅里 给你们现场直播
I'm here at my NOLA pad live streaming to you at home.
给你们可悲的生活
Bringing a little something-something.
带来点光彩吧
into your pathetic little lives.
看看这些新奥尔良的婊子
Look at these NOLA bitches.
我等会要干哪一个 不不 哪两个呢
Which one… No, which two am I gonna fuck after.
喂 对女士们放尊重点
Oi. Have some respect for the ladies.
我在这直播呢
I am live streaming here.
你们相信这些废话吗 看看这家伙
You guys believe this shit Look at this guy.
他以为自己是谁呢
Who does this motherfucker think he is.
喂 尊重女士们
"Oi, respect the ladies."
我会尊重她们的
I'll respect them all right.
尊重她们 让她们舔掉我蛋蛋上的汗水
Respect them enough to let them lick the sweat off my balls.
该死 伙计 我的鼻子
Fuck, dude, my nose.
你知道我靠这张脸赚了多少钱吗 混蛋
Do you know how much money I make off this face, asshole.
去他妈的
Fuck it.
（绝密文件）
欢迎回家
Welcome home,
亲爱的
love.
你该庆幸我没朝你开枪
You're lucky I didn't shoot you.
可能吧
Probably.
嘿 你现在能看懂吗
Hey, do you read now.
这是什么
What is this.
你们要去什么地方 是吗
Going somewhere, are we.
我要抓住杀害巴尼的凶手
We're going after the guy that got Barney.
巴尼的死 唯一的好处就是公布了这份文件
The only good thing that came out of Barney's death was the unsealing of that file.
这到底是什么意思 这里写了什么
What the fuck does that mean What's in here.
好吧
Well,
巴尼参与了多个国际机构
Barney was part of a classified operation.
合作的秘密行动
in between international agencies.
事情败露后 所有相关方决定封存档案
And when it went south, all the parties involved decided to seal the file.
直到所有参与行动的人都死光
until everyone associated with it was dead.
所以 巴尼死后这份文件就被解密了
So once Barney passed, that file was declassified.
这让我们了解了豹猫的身份
It gave us a vital clue on Ocelot's identity.
我要加入 我要和你一起去
I want in. I'm coming with you.
我很抱歉
Oh, I'm sorry.
你没有被邀请
You weren't invited.
没有我 你不会感到寂寞吗
Well, won't you be lonely without me.
不会
No.
还有很多帅哥一起执行任务呢
There's lots of other boys on the mission.
我没那个心情
I'm not in the mood.
我给你表演个小本·亨德里克斯
I'm gonna play a little Hendrix.
- 通常很管用 - 别说了
- Usually does the trick. - Don't start.
我开始了
I'm starting.
我一直很喜欢这个纹身
Oh, I always liked this tattoo.
你兄弟也是
So did your brother.
这一直是我在家里最喜欢的座位
This was always my favorite seat in the house.
好吧 这座位可不白坐
Well, these and the cheap seats.
你得小心点
You really need to be more careful.
说服我
Make me.
帮老战友一个忙吧
Do an old soldier a favor.
先办急事
First things first.
当我第一次见到巴尼的时候…
When I first met Barney…
我刚从特种部队退役
I was straight out of the SAS.
我没有钱 处境很困难
Nothing to my name, down on my luck.
在别人都不愿意的时候 他给了我机会
He took a chance on me when no one else would.
我们会抓到杀害巴尼的凶手
We're gonna get the guy that did this to Barney.
我向你保证
I promise.
我知道我不能和你一起去
I know I can't go with you.
但我希望你带上这个
But I want you to take this.
可好
Well,
我会代你向拉赫马特问好的
I'll make sure to give Rahmat your regards.
（搜索信号中…）
（搜索信号）
（跟踪已完成）
好大个尾背耳（粤语）
That's a big, curly ear.
你听懂了吗
You catch any of that.
我不知道她在说什么
I don't know what she's saying.
- 你觉得为什么别人叫她鞭妹 - 我不知道
- But why do you think they call her Lash - I have no idea.
但我想知道 她可以随时鞭打我
But I'd love to find out. She can lash me anytime.
哦 它比那个大得多亲爱的
Oh, it's way bigger than that, darling.
不 不 那是中国的鸟
No, no. That's the Chinese bird.
我们用中指 他们用小指
We use the middle finger, they use the pinky.
但如果合适的话…
But if the shoe fits…
我是说你的耳朵怎么了
I was saying what's up with your ears.
- 我的耳朵 - 哦 糟糕
- My ear - Oh, shit.
好吧 大家都知道我在大学里是玩摔跤的
Well, everybody knows I wrestled in college.
这项运动的一个常见后果就是耳朵挫伤
And a common affliction in that sport is that you get a contusion in the ear.
皮肤与软骨被分开最后形成这样的饺子耳
that separates the cartilage from the skin and creates a little pocket.
这个已经是第九次了
I've had this one drained nine times.
我从没见过他这么冷静
I've never seen him so quiet.
从本质上说上帝给了我盔甲
In essence, God gave me armor.
自从巴尼死后 他什么都没说
He hasn't said anything since Barney died.
有一次我发现我的室友在谈论这件事
Now, I caught my roommate talking shit about it one time.
我不得不按着头把他的耳朵拧成花椰菜
And I had to smack him upside his head and give him his own cauliflower ear.
事情就是这样
That's just the way it goes.
你想感受一下吗 不想吗
You want to feel it No.
不会传染的 我保证
It's not contagious. I promise.
（美 国 中央情报局 南海基地）
（泰国）
你好 打听一下
How you doing, friend.
我在找德夏
I'm looking for Decha.
德夏·尤奈
Disha yunai.
谁
Who.
他是前泰国特种部队 第90师的
Ex-Task Force 90. Thailand Special Forces.
据说他有一艘船停靠在这附近
Supposedly owns a boat that docks around here.
在这里 我不认识这样的人
Don't know anyone around here like that.
但是如果他有一艘船
But if he have boat,
船在下面 而不是在这里
boat down there, not up here.
谢谢你的帮助
Thanks for your help.
嘿 打扰一下朋友
Hey, excuse me, friend.
你认识这艘船的主人吗
You know the owner of this boat.
我在找一个叫德夏的人
I'm looking for a man named Decha.
抱歉 德夏很久以前就走了
I'm sorry. Decha has long gone.
是吗 去哪了
Oh, yeah Where.
去一个宁静的地方
To a place of peace.
死了吗
Dead.
是的 这很常见的
Yeah, well, there's a lot of that going around.
抱歉
Excuse me.
先生 我不能让你偷走这艘船
I can't let you steal this boat, sir.
对你来说是什么
What's it to you.
就是一艘船
Just a boat.
但不是你的
It's not yours.
听着 不管你同不同意 我都要这艘船
Hey, listen, I'm taking this boat with or without your permission.
你怎么会有巴尼的戒指
Why do you have Barney's ring.
巴尼死了
Barney's dead.
我需要这艘船来找到杀害他的人
And I need this boat to get to the people who killed him.
我在找德夏
I was looking for Decha.
从巴尼对他的评价来看 他接下来会有很大的作用
From what Barney said about the man, I could use him for what's ahead.
巴尼死了
Barney's dead.
我以前叫德夏 你要找的人
I was once Decha, the man you seek.
但是我已经放下过去了
But I put that man behind me.
如果你说的是真的
If what you say is true,
我得为巴尼报仇
Barney should have his revenge.
太对了 就应该这么干
Damn right, he should.
好了 大家听好了
Okay, listen up.
泰国金塔拉号货轮被劫持
The Thai cargo ship Jintara was hijacked.
我们的朋友拉赫马特在安达曼海
in the Andaman Sea by our mutual friend Rahmat.
金塔拉改变了路线
The Jintara has changed course.
它现在正驶向俄罗斯的海参崴海岸
and is tracking en route to the Russian coast of Vladivostok.
现在 由于利比亚的皇室混乱
Now, due to that royal clusterfuck that was Libya,
拉赫马特已经拥有了核装置
Rahmat has taken possession of the nuclear detonators.
这艘船将举行一场交易
The ship itself is gonna be hosting an exchange.
在那里 他们将获得制造核弹
where they'll be taking possession of the remaining nuclear materials.
所需的剩余核材料
needed to construct a viable bomb, nuclear type.
我们不能让这种情况发生 明白了吗
And we cannot let that happen. Understood.
我们得到消息说
Now, we also have valuable intel that says.
豹猫在金特拉号货船上
that Ocelot will be on the Jintara.
所以也许这是唯一一个揭露他身份的机会
So this might be our one and only chance to learn of his true identity.
- 或者她 - 你说什么
- Or her. - What's that.
也可能是个女人
Could be a her.
或者「她」的身份 是的
Or her identity, yes.
然后我们逮捕他或她
And bring him or her in.
大家都知道 巴尼的死揭露了这份文件
As you know, Barney's death opened up a file.
揭露了和豹猫一起工作的人的名字
that reveals the name of a man who worked with Ocelot.
一个在证人保护计划中的证人
A witness in witness protection.
从鲁索那里了解更多他的信息
More on him from Russo.
他的名字叫他叫潘龙白
Name's Phen Lyong Bai.
豹猫的前搭档 他很乐意透露豹猫的事
Ocelot's former partner who'd love to rat Ocelot out.
告密者是没有好下场的 对吧 贡纳
Snitches get stitches. Right, Gunner.
没错 告密者没有好下场
That's right. Snitches get stitches.
不用我说你也知道这次任务有多棘手
I don't have to tell you how sensitive this mission is.
如果俄罗斯人得到风声说美军不仅在领土附近
If the Russians get wind that the US forces are not only near.
而且在俄罗斯领土内
but inside Russian territory,
这会引起第三次世界大战级别的混乱
it's a World War III shit show.
明白吗
Understood.
因此这次任务没有美国方面的签字
So that's why this mission carries no US signature whatsoever.
美国会完全否认
Full deniability.
如果事情失控了 你们只能靠自己 然后最后一件事
If this goes bad, it's on you. And one last thing.
既然你们在没有我的情况下搞砸了在利比亚最后的任务
Since you Neanderthals dicked up that last mission in Libya without me,
这次我和你一起去
I'm gonna be coming along to babysit you this time.
是不是很有趣 吉娜
Now, won't that be fun Gina.
好吧 这次任务就是这样
All right, so the mission's gonna go down like this.
我们将分两队进行这次攻击 每个队都有一个单独的目标
We're gonna run this assault as a split team with two separate objectives.
我们进去后
We're gonna HALO in.
A队要守住舰桥
Team Alpha's gonna secure the bridge.
B队要彻底搜查这艘船
while Bravo searches and sweeps the boat.
我们要找到并杀死豹猫和拉赫马特
We're gonna identify, kill-capture both Ocelot and Rahmat,
确保炸药和核部件的安全 然后坐直升机撤离
secure the detonators and the nuclear components, helo extract.
有什么问题吗
Any questions.
我对任务的说明和巴尼不一样吗
Is my delivery a little different than Barney's.
他可能会说 「我们上吧」
He probably would have just said, "Let's go."
是的
Yeah.
好吧…
Well…
我们上吧
let's go.
这是一把斧头吗
Is that an axe.
不 这只是一把雪铲
No, it's a snow shovel.
有道理 对你来说 就说得通了
That makes sense. Not for humanity, but for you it makes sense.
所以你的故事是什么
Hey. So what's your story.
巴尼告诉我 你是前90师前特遣部队的
Barney told me you were ex-Task Force 90.
顶级杀手
Ultimate killer type.
他从没见过比他更快更好的人
Never seen anyone faster or better.
你能杀人的次数有限 圣诞
There's only so many times you can kill a man, Christmas.
每一次
Each time,
它都变得更容易
it gets easier.
你对痛苦、快乐和爱都变得麻木了
You become numb to pain, to joy, and to love.
每杀一个人
With every person you kill,
你就失去了更多的自我
you lose a little more of yourself.
我必须在失去一切之前停下来
I had to stop before there was nothing left.
我想我现在该用斧头了
Figured I'd be using my axe by now.
这里太安静了 有点不对劲
This is too quiet. Something ain't right.
轻松哥 鞭妹 你们跟我来 其他人绕到左舷船尾
Easy Day, Lash, you're with me. The rest of you, swing around port quarter.
左舷船尾在哪儿来着
Where's port quarter again.
我是陆军 我们常说的是左右 而不是港口和星舰什么的
I was Army. We said left and right, not port and starship shit.
右舷是右边
Starboard is right.
左舷在左边 船尾在后面
Port, left. Quarter, back.
- 明白了 - 我们上吧
- Got it. - Let's move.
我有种不好的预感
Got a bad feeling about this.
是啊 人都去哪了
Yeah, where the hell is everybody.
核弹肯定在飞机上
The nuke is definitely onboard.
听着 我有个坏消息
All right, listen up. Bad news.
他们已经有了铀和核弹头
They already have uranium with the detonators.
这艘船目前有一枚有效的核弹
There is now an active nuclear bomb on the ship.
我们就要过舰桥了
We're about to take the bridge.
它就像一个鬼城
It's a ghost town in here.
快 放下你们的武器
Go Put your weapons down now.
他妈的 真是一团糟
What a fucking mess this turned out to be.
先是利比亚 现在又是这样
First Libya, now this.
两次都有人知道我们要来
Somebody knew we were coming. Both times.
我的情报很可靠
My intel was solid.
- 你的情报太糟糕了 - 啊 糟透了
- Your intel was shit. - Ah, shit on this.
情报可能已经泄露了
The intel could have been leaked.
- 我们对你不了解 - 他是没问题的
- We don't know you. - He was verified.
好吧 那可能是你的新女友有问题
Well, then maybe it was your new girlfriend.
去你妈的 贡纳
Fuck you, Gunner.
你已经在维尔纽斯的任务上出卖了我们
You sold us out in Vilena on that mission.
你以为我会忘记这件事吗
Think I'd forget about that.
确实有人出卖了我们
Somebody did sell us out.
那你的男人呢
How about your man.
你为了上位出卖了他
You sold him out so you could be on top.
冷静点 她不会那样做的
Back off. She wouldn't do that.
那为什么 要顶替他
What Fuck him on top.
去你妈的
Fuck you.
也许是角落里那个沉默的人
Maybe it's the mute over in the corner.
怎么了加兰 说不出来话了
What's up, Galan Cat got your tongue, cowboy.
- 是的 他有所隐瞒 - 的确
- Yeah, he's hiding something. - Yeah.
我从来不相信这个该死的家伙
I never trusted this fucking guy.
- 谁是头儿 - 我是
- Who's the leader - I'm the leader.
把他带走
Take him.
妈的
Fuck.
她在那里
There she is.
开始吧
Go time.
我先去
I'll go first.
等我发出信号 你就跟过来
Send down a signal when it's clear for you to follow.
我只能到这里了
This is as far as I go.
- 我需要你 - 我不行
- I could use you. - I can't.
如果我把过去的我放出来
If I let the old me out,
我不知道我还能不能让他回去
I don't know if I could ever get him back in.
我明白
I understand.
这里应该是一场大屠杀
Should be carnage up here.
你们在哪里
Where are you guys.
我下班了 我要下楼了
My shift's done. Going downstairs.
不要动 转过身来
Don't move and turn around.
慢慢地
Slowly.
好吧 到底是哪一个呢 朋友
Well, which one is it, friend.
不要动还是慢慢转身
Don't move or turn around slowly.
转身
Turn around.
慢慢地
Very slowly.
哦 我的天啊
Ah Jesus Christ.
科林 你把我吓得要死你个笨蛋
Colin, you scared the shit out of me, you bellend.
科林 他妈的谁是科林
Colin Who the fuck is Colin.
少来这套 嘿 你得小心点
Don't give me that. Hey, you need to be careful with that.
它可能会在你手里爆炸
That could go off in your hand.
来得正是时候 马什先生
Perfect timing, Mr. Marsh.
马什
Marsh.
这次任务是个圈套
This mission was a trap.
有人泄露了我们的情报
Somebody leaked our intel.
我的要求很简单
My demands are simple.
囚犯交换
Prisoner exchange.
我要你的囚犯 潘龙白
I want your prisoner, Phen Lyong Bai.
我朋友的好朋友
A dear friend of a friend.
如果不答应
If not,
马什先生会证明我是认真的
Mr. Marsh will be the example of how deadly serious I am.
所以你会怎么做 鲁索
So, what's it going to be, Russo.
我没有这个权力
I don't have the authority.
我知道你没有
I know you don't.
但是…我知道有个人会这么做
But I know someone who does.
把最后一架假飞机架起来
Let's get the last of the fake planes up.
拉赫马特
Rahmat,
你这个狡猾的小香肠
you sneaky little sausage.
我可以给你授权
I can get you the authority.
潘龙白在你的监狱里
Phen Lyong Bai is in your lockup.
你的联系人是唐纳德·乌尔曼 授权号：2-2-5-7-9
Your contact is Donald Allman, authorization 2-2-5-7-9.
好样的
Good.
不许耍花招
And no funny business.
敢死队的死活
It's your call whether the Expendables.
取决于你的决定
need to live up to their namesake or not.
（搜索信号）
（追踪完成）
给你们可悲的生活
Bringing a little something-something.
带来点光彩吧
into your pathetic little lives.
看看这些婊子
Look at these bitches.
我等会要干哪一个 不不 哪两个呢
Which one… No, which two am I gonna fuck after.
嘿 对女士们放尊重点
Oi. Have some respect for the ladies.
我在这直播呢
I am live streaming here.
你们相信这些废话吗 看看这家伙
You guys believe this shit Look at this guy.
看着这家伙 我崇拜他 他是我的英雄
Watch this guy, I love him, he is my hero.
我会尊重她们的
I'll respect them all right.
尊重她们 她们就会舔掉我蛋蛋上的汗水
Respect them enough to let them lick the sweat off my balls.
我希望有一天能见到他
I hope to meet him one day.
这把刀不是你的
This doesn't belong to you.
我的队友们在哪
Where are my friends.
长官 我们可能遇到麻烦了
Sir, we might have a problem.
与佩顿和塔克失去联系
Paithoon and Takk have gone dark.
二楼657房间
Room 657, B-deck.
非常感谢
Much appreciated.
贡纳
Gunner.
- 呼叫塔克 - 不要介意哦
- Takk - Don't mind if I do.
报告情况 塔克 我们船上可能有只老鼠
Report back, Takk. We may have a rat onboard.
检查每个人的状况
Check everyone's status.
塔克
Takk.
塔克目前无法回复
Takk can't come to the phone right now.
他有点瘸了
He's a little limp.
你是谁
Who is this.
一个不小心让你跑了的人
A man who made a mistake letting you live.
但我是来补救的
But I'm here to remedy that.
看看是谁想当英雄
Look who's still trying to be a hero.
你能上船真是太好了
How nice of you to come aboard.
如果你希望能解决利比亚的问题 很抱歉你来晚了
If you're hoping for a redo of the mess in Libya, you're too late, I'm afraid.
我的人正赶来送你上路
My men are on their way to hunt you down.
所以我想应该让你早点入土为安了
So I guess it's up to me to put you in an early grave.
就像在利比亚我对你朋友做的那样
Just like I did your friend in Libya.
纠正一下 他不是我的朋友
Correction. He wasn't my friend.
他是我的兄弟
He was my brother.
你可以带上你的军队
So you can bring your army.
把你的人都带来
Bring all the fucking men you want.
我会一个一个地解决他们
and I'll work through every last one of them.
要是我抓到你
When I get to you,
我会确保你离开这艘船的唯一方式
I'll make sure that the only way you leave this ship.
就是碎尸万段
is in a wonderful variety of pieces.
不要对着炸弹开枪
Don't shoot by the bomb.
帕维尔 你看到老鼠了吗
Pavel, you have eyes on the rat.
- 是的长官 - 位置
- Yes, sir. - Location.
一楼走廊
Corridor, deck one.
- 第二层甲板 - 什么东西
- Deck two. - What.
军官餐厅 三甲板
Officers' dining area, deck three.
一路走好 朋友
Rubber side down, mate.
他在船尾
He's on the stern.
你干嘛呢
What are you doing.
我以为你不会再过这种生活了
Thought you were done with this life.
让巴尼的朋友死是对巴尼的不尊重
It would be disrespectful to Barney's memory to let his friend die.
我喜欢这个造型
I like the look.
谢谢你
Thank you.
- 那我们开始吧 - 好的
- Then let's get to it. - Okay.
这里一切都封得严严实实
Everything's sealed tight down here.
没错 焊接得也很好
Yeah, these are welded up solid too.
好吧 那接下来呢
Okay, so what's next.
舱底排水系统
Bilge system.
- 什么 - 舱底的排水系统
- What - Bilge system.
在紧急情况下 水会被排到船上干燥的地方
In emergencies, it clears water from the ship's dry areas.
如果你能打开它 我们应该就能离开这里
If you get it open, it should let us out of here.
来吧伙计 让我们把这该死的东西打开
Come on, man. Let's get this fucking thing open.
- 哦 根本没动 - 别废话 得弄湿才行
- Well, that ain't budging. - No shit. It's got to get wet.
什么
What.
如果它是湿的 就可以打开
Wet. If it gets wet, it'll open.
- 好吧 有人想小便吗 - 我要尿尿
- Well, anybody gotta pee - I gotta go.
我们跳伞到这里后 我还没尿过尿
I've had to piss since we HALO'd in here.
请给我一点隐私好吗
A little privacy, please.
舌骨
The hyoid bone.
它是人体中唯一一块与其他骨骼没有连接的骨骼
It's the only bone in the human body not connected to any others.
它就在嘴里 没有它你就没法说话
It's right here in the throat. Without it, we cannot speak.
我要用手 把拉赫马特那个混蛋的舌骨
With these hands, I will claw the hyoid bone.
从喉咙里拔出来
from the throat of that fucker Rahmat,
插进他男朋友的屁眼里
stick it up his boyfriend's culo,
然后让他们两个都道歉
then make both of their asses apologize.
最后让他们溺死在自己的血液里
while they drown in their own blood.
巴尼是我的榜样
Barney was my hero.
我不想说了 我不能说了
I do not speak, I cannot speak,
因为我的脑子里充满了这些残酷的幻想
because my mind is full of these brutal, visceral fantasies,
想象一下我会把它变成可怕的现实
fantasies that will now become a hellish reality.
你应该继续保持沉默
You should go back to not talking.
- 好了 - 谁愿意钻进去
- Done. - Any takers.
这能帮我们找到杀害巴尼的凶手吗
This will lead us to the men who killed Barney.
啊 是的
Uh, yes.
我要为他报仇
I will avenge him.
原来他喜欢「黄金雨」
Guess he does like golden showers.
我们说话这会儿 龙白已经在路上了
Lyong Bai is en route to you as we speak.
我希望我的队员能活着回来
I expect to have my team returned alive.
当然可以 不信守承诺还算什么男人呢
Of course. For what is a man without his word.
做好交换的准备
Prepare for exchange.
出发了
Moving out.
- 这边走 - 好
- This way. - Okay.
你的队友见到你一定会很高兴的 对吧
Your friends will be really happy to see you, right.
大概不会吧
Probably not.
吉娜会不得不承认她需要我
Gina will have to admit she needs me.
- 数到三 - 好
- On three. - Yeah.
三
Three.
这里没人
Nobody here.
不是吧
No shit.
他们去哪了
Where did they go.
你闻到尿味了吗
You smell piss.
是的
Yeah.
我们要保持安静 直到该大声说话时
We're gonna stay quiet until it's time to get loud.
来 来 这边
Okay, okay. Yeah.
趴在地上
Get on the ground.
是时候大声说话了吗
Time to get loud.
你才需要趴在地上 伙计
It's you who needs to get down on the ground, pal.
不然怎样
Or what.
不然会被敢死队干掉
Or get wasted by an Expendable.
别告诉我 你见到我很高兴
Don't tell me. You're happy to see me.
严格来说你已经不是敢死队了 圣诞
Technically, you're not an Expendable anymore, Christmas.
尤其是你
Especially you.
- 很高兴见到你 - 我也是
- Such a pleasure. - Likewise.
时机很好 轻松哥
Great timing. Easy Day.
圣诞快乐
Feliz Navidad.
这是我的斧头吗
Is that my Traumahawk.
- 是的 - 你喜欢吗
- Yeah. - How do you like it.
- 我越来越喜欢了 - 你怎么这么久才来
- Growing on me. - What took you so long.
你以为我会相信
Did you think that I was gonna believe.
你只是把刀送给我吗
you were actually just gifting me your knife.
你把你的刀送给她了
You gifted her your knife.
他们说浪漫已死
And they say romance is dead.
他在刀里放了追踪器 不过这都是我计划的一部分
He put a tracker in it. It was all part of the plan.
抱歉了
Sorry.
我觉得有点被利用了
I feel a little used.
好了 我们走吧
Okay, let's go.
嘿 贡纳 注意身后
Hey, Gunner, watch our six.
我喜欢你的头发
I like your hair.
- 你的新朋友是谁 - 德夏
- Who's your new friend - Decha.
巴尼的老朋友 他们中的佼佼者
Old friend of Barney's. Kicks ass with the best of them.
巴尼的朋友对我来说都很好
Any friend of Barney's is all right by me.
- 拉赫马特绑架了马什 - 我很难过
- Rahmat took Marsh. - I'm devastated.
当务之急 托尔·罗德 我需要你看一样东西
First things first. Toll Road, I need you to take a look at something.
这是一个巨大的炸弹
It's a big fucking bomb.
我们没拿到的核炸药
With the detonators that we didn't get.
我们完蛋了
We're fucked.
你能详细说明吗
Can you elaborate.
这玩意儿27分钟后就会爆炸
This thing's wired to go in 27 minutes.
它是防篡改的 有水银开关
It's tamperproof. Got mercury switches.
关闭这玩意儿的唯一方法就是找到远程终止开关
The only way we're shutting this bad boy down is to find the remote kill switch.
那是最后一道防线
That's the last line of defense.
它是近距离控制
Now, it's short range,
所以不管谁带着它 都会在这艘船上
so whoever has that on their person is on this fucking boat.
- 拉赫马特 - 拉赫马特
- Rahmat. - Rahmat.
谁是拉赫马特
Who's Rahmat.
就是他杀了巴尼
Guy who killed Barney.
我们可能刚进入俄罗斯海域
We probably just entered Russian waters.
这艘船被装扮成了一艘美国航空母舰
Dressing this ship to look like a US aircraft carrier.
并且带着一枚即将在俄罗斯海岸爆炸的核弹
with a primed nuke about to blow off the coast of Russia.
这将引发第三次世界大战
It's going to start World War III.
时间紧迫 准备行动
Clock is ticking. Let's lock and load.
新位置 甲板边
New location, deckside.
现在的关键就是这个终止开关
It's all about this kill switch now.
干掉拉赫马特才能终止
Switch off Rahmat permanently.
好吧 你能给我们做个「又吵又闹的家伙」吗
Well, can you make us something loud and messy.
教皇会在树林里拉屎吗
Does the pope shit in the woods.
不 教皇不会在树林里拉屎
No, the pope don't shit in the woods.
也不会在一只熊旁边拉屎 你为什么要问这个
Or next to a bear. Why you gotta say shit like that.
那是什么
What is that.
妈的 炸弹
Oh, shit Bomb.
该死
Shit.
他妈的
Fuck it.
不用谢
You're welcome.
别客气
Don't mention it.
很高兴回来
Good to be back.
我支持你
I got you.
谢谢你
Thanks.
嘿 混蛋
Hey, puta.
我来对付他
I got him.
托尔·罗德
Toll Road.
轻松哥 有人受伤了
Easy Man down Man down.
你能亲一下吗 那会让我好受点
Can you kiss that and make it better.
晚点吧 我现在有点忙
Maybe later. I'm a little busy right now.
我来处理
I got him.
准备交换囚犯
Ready for prisoner exchange.
三分钟后着陆
Three minutes until we touch down.
准备交易
Standing by for the exchange.
按计划进行
Proceed as planned.
你好吗 拉赫马特
How you doing, Rahmat.
我看你喜欢玩刀
I see you like to play with knives.
现在不玩了
Well, I ain't playing no more.
把终止开关给我 我们就能结束这一切
You're gonna give me the kill switch, and we're gonna end all this.
来拿啊 英雄
Come and get it, hero.
这是你最拿手的吗
Is that the biggest one you've got.
不
Nah.
这才是我最拿手的
That's the biggest one I got.
李 你还好吗
Lee, you good.
很好
Yeah.
终止开关在哪
Where's the kill switch.
你这个混蛋 我没有终止开关
You fucking idiot. I don't have the kill switch.
我老板有
My boss has it.
豹猫
Ocelot.
潘龙白来了
Phen Lyong Bai is here.
他是能认出豹猫的证人
He's our witness that can identify Ocelot.
- 你好 白 - 哦 我的天哪 不
- Hello, Bai. - Oh, my God, no.
- 不 - 再见了 白
- No - Bye-bye, Bai.
马什就是豹猫
Marsh is Ocelot.
终止开关一直都在他那里
He's had the kill switch this whole…
这是给巴尼的
That's for Barney.
还有多久会爆炸
How long until detonation.
12分钟
Twelve minutes.
好了 我们有12分钟
All right, we got 12 minutes.
让船像烟花一样爆炸吧
before this ship blows up like a Roman candl…
嘿 马什 我想你不再需要那个了
Hey, Marsh. I guess you won't be needing that anymore.
好了 圣诞
All right, Christmas.
你就像有性病一样
You're like genital warts.
总是出现在不该出现的地方 而且赶都赶不走
Always showing up where you're not wanted and refusing to go away.
你有我想要的东西 马什
You got something I need, Marsh.
我下来拿
I'm coming down to get it.
我猜你发现了这个装置
I guess you figured out that this device right here.
是唯一能阻止第三次世界大战的东西
is the only thing preventing World War III,
这场冲突虽然对很多人来说是毁灭性的
a conflict that, while devastating for many,
但也同样是疯狂的
it'll be insanely,
疯狂的
insanely,
给某个人带来了疯狂的利润
insanely profitable for somebody.
那个人就是我
And that somebody is gonna be me.
敢死队会承担所有的责任
And the Expendables will take all the blame.
所以好好欣赏这场表演吧
So, enjoy the show.
杀光他们
Kill them all.
找掩护
Take cover.
所有人趴下
Everybody get down.
我们得离开这艘船 不然我们都会被炸死
We need to get clear of this boat or we're all gonna get fried.
现在来看跳海是个不错的计划
Jumping overboard is seeming like a decent plan right now.
我们不可能逃出爆炸区 时间不够了
We'll never make it out of the blast zone. We'll never make it in time.
嘿 伙计 你不能在我眼皮底下死去
Hey, man, you're not going down on my watch.
我们得走了 他失血过多
We gotta move. He's bleeding out.
我有个主意
I got an idea.
我们可以坐我的船 它在后面拖着呢
We can take my boat. It's being towed.
这是个好主意
That's a great idea.
接下来我们就从这里动身
Next time, let's start with that.
好
Yeah.
贡纳 火力掩护 我们要出去了
Gunner, give us cover fire. We're on the way out.
收到 火力掩护
Copy that. Cover fire.
在船尾会合 重复 在船尾会合
Meet at the stern. Repeat, meet at the stern.
我们得走了
We gotta move.
我看到他们去了另一边
I saw them go to the other side.
舰桥上没人 开始搜船
There's no one on the bridge. Start searching the ship.
托尔·罗德 下一个就是你了
Toll Road, you're next.
加兰 该你了
Galan, you're up.
怎么了
What.
没什么
Never mind.
走吧
Let's go.
任务优先
Mission first.
我得让这艘船掉头
I gotta turn this ship around.
让我的牺牲有价值
Make my sacrifice count.
这是他自己的决定
It's his decision to make.
德夏 我们得走了 不然托尔·罗德就撑不住了
Decha, we need to move or Toll Road's not gonna make it.
（锚1号）
把剩下的充气船弄上来
Get the rest of the inflatable boats up here.
长官 我们的船掉头驶向大海了
Sir, we're headed back out to sea.
快 快 快
Move it, move it, move it, people.
他妈的性病男
Genital fucking warts.
干掉他
Take him out.
去给汽艇充气
Get that RIB inflated.
我们需要让船回到正轨
We need to get the ship back on course.
到舰桥上去把这个修好
Get up to the bridge and fix this.
但是长官…
But, sir…
但是什么
But, sir, what.
核弹要爆炸了 我们不能上去
The nuke is gonna blow. We can't go up…
你觉得升职怎么样
How do you feel about a promotion.
都到舰桥上去
All to the bridge.
干掉他 所有人上舰桥 快 快
Take him down All to the bridge Go, go.
看来我们很快就能见面了 巴尼
Looks like I'll be seeing you soon, Barney.
圣诞
Christmas.
我在这里 马什
Right here, Marsh.
我看你把骑兵都叫来了
I see you called in the cavalry.
不过你摆脱不了我
Well, you can't get rid of me.
尝试才有乐趣
Well, the fun's in trying.
你为什么不下来面对面谈谈呢
Why don't you come down face-to-face.
单挑
Man-to-man.
老一套
Old school.
那就别怪我了
Don't mind if I do.
我都等不及了
Can't wait.
你他妈的别动 我马上下来
Don't you fucking move I'll be right down.
巴尼25年前试图揭发我 但他失败了
Barney tried to expose me 25 years ago, and he failed.
但你 你是个好士兵
But you, you're a good soldier.
你是个非常优秀的士兵
You're a very good soldier.
但是这个超出了你的能力范围
But this, I mean, this is above and beyond.
这是更高的层次
This… This is next level.
巴尼会为你感到骄傲的
Barney would be proud of you.
你可以亲自告诉他
Well, you can tell him yourself.
因为你马上就要去见他了
Because you're about to join him.
非常好
So very nice.
看看圣诞老人给我带来了什么
Look what Santa brought me.
搞什么鬼
The fuck.
巴尼
Barney.
嘿 我马上要用经典神器干掉了他
Hey, I had him with the classics.
你他妈的差点杀了我
You almost fucking killed me.
不用谢
You're welcome.
快上来
Come on.
这他妈是怎么回事
The fuck is happening.
抓紧了
Hold on.
- 核弹在哪里 - 在船尾
- Where are the nukes - In the stern.
嘿 你已经死了啊
Hey, you were dead.
- 到底怎么回事 - 我有点忙
- The hell's going on - I'm a little busy.
到底是怎么回事
So what's the story.
25年前 我们执行了一项秘密任务
Twenty-five years ago, we were doing a covert op,
我的八名队员被消灭了
and eight of my team got wiped out.
我不得不伪造自己的死亡来公开一份机密文件
I had to fake my own death to open up a classified file,
把马什引出来 这样我才能证明他是豹猫
driving Marsh out of hiding so I could prove he's Ocelot.
你为什么瞒着我们
Why'd you keep it from us.
如果我没有接那个秘密任务 我的队员都还会活着
If I didn't take that job, they'd all be alive.
所以这是私人恩怨
So, it was personal.
你懂的
You understand.
我需要喝一杯
I need a drink.
我也是
Me too.
- 你请客 - 我破产了
- You're buying. - I'm broke.
这话比你死的时候更搞笑
You were funnier when you were dead.
很高兴又和你在一起了
Great spending time with you again.
但你需要洗个澡
But you could use a shower.
（悼念巴尼·罗斯队长）
托尔·罗德 你欠我20块
Toll Road, you owe me 20 bucks.
我想你不需要戴眼镜了
Guess you won't be needing glasses.
还不错
Not bad.
向我那些永不放弃的朋友们致敬
Salute to my friends who never quit.
为你们所有人干杯
Cheers to you all.
- 干杯 - 干杯
- Salud. - Salute.
向你们致敬
To you guys.
船上那句老掉牙的话怎么说来着 圣诞
What about that corny quote on the ship, Christmas.
- 你不用再重复了 托尔·罗德 - 「让我的牺牲有价值 」
- You don't need to repeat that, Toll Road. - "Make my sacrifice count "
是啊 去你的吧
Yeah, fuck you.
别再为难他了
Stop giving him such a hard time.
我觉得这很甜蜜
I think it's sweet.
啊 真甜蜜
Aw. That's sweet.
他们都嫉妒你 因为你是最帅的
They're all just jealous because you're the most handsome one.
我知道
I know.
爱情不是很美好吗
Ain't love beautiful.
嘿 托尔·罗德
Hey, Toll Road.
真的吗
Really.
巴尼·罗斯 起死回生
Barney Ross, back from the dead.
只有你能毫发无伤地从熊熊烈火中走出来
Only you could walk away from a blazing inferno with not a scratch on you.
你就像一只凤凰 浴火重生
You are like a mythical bird raising up from the ashes.
- 我不明白你是怎么做到的 - 等一下
- I don't know how you do it. - Just a moment.
我很放松 我在跟我的英雄说话呢
I am relaxed. I'm trying to talk to my hero over here.
你能给我点空间吗 轻松哥
Would you give me some space please, Easy Day.
嘿 笨蛋 有时间吗
Hey, lame brain, you got a minute.
- 当然有 - 一个小问题
- Of course. - A minor question.
过来吧
Step right in.
它来了 一个破戒指
There it is. Piece of junk.
我想死这个了
I missed this.
- 谢谢 我的朋友 - 嗯
- Thanks, my friend. - Yeah.
- 我想知道 - 尸体是谁
- I need to know. - Who the corpse is.
没错
Exactly.
你有没有想过珍宝虾怎么了
You ever wonder what happened to Jumbo Shrimp.
警告 前方地势太低
Warning. Terrain ahead. Too low.
警告 没有起落装置 请拉升
Warning. No landing gear. Pull up.
你没在飞机上面
You didn't.
是的 我跳伞了
Oh, yes, I did.